<resources>

    <string name="radar_overview_body">Airborne Radars were added to the game in Update 1.87 "Locked On". Airborne radars are found on aircraft at both low and high ranks, if an aircraft is equipped with radar then a radar display will be present in the right portion of a player\'s screen, as well as a compass displaying the player\'s current heading and the directions to detected targets at the top of the screen.\n\nThere are two main types of airborne radar in the game, target detection (search) radars and target tracking radars. Target detection radars will detect aircraft (both friendly and hostile) and display them as a "blip" on the radar display, it will also place a triangle on the compass showing what direction the detected aircraft is in. Target tracking radars are more advanced; they allow the player to "lock-on" to a target. Once a target has been locked on to, a box will appear around it on the HUD and a read-out will provide the distance to the target and the closing speed between the player\'s aircraft and the target. Depending on the aircraft being flown tracking radars may also be able to provide an accurate firing lead indicator, once the player closes to within approximately 0.7 km.</string>

    <string name="basic_user_interface_body">As previously mentioned, aircraft equipped with radars can be identified by the presence of the radar display and compass on the HUD.\n\nBelow the linear compass at top centre is a small arrow which displays the aircraft\'s current heading. Targets detected by the radar will also have their bearing displayed on the compass as a triangle.\n\nOne or two radar scopes will be present in the right hand portion of the screen; they are discussed in detail later in the article. If the radar is experiencing surface clutter interference then an icon (visible in the image to the right) will be present next to the power indicator, consisting of two arrows and a series of bars. The number of bars illuminated indicates how severe surface clutter is (one bar means minor interference, four bars means major interference); if the aircraft has two radars activated then each one will have its own surface clutter indicator.\n\nIf the radar has been deactivated, a separate icon will be displayed instead of the radar display.\n\nThere are several different types of radar target which can appear on the radar display and compass. A basic radar target will appear as a bar on the radar display and a triangle on the compass. The radar target which is selected will appear with a vertical line either side of it; and the radar target which is locked on to will appear with a box around it. Some radars are fitted with Identification Friend or Foe (IFF) systems, these radars will display friendly radar targets with a horizontal line above them.</string>

    <string name="ppi_body">The default display is a "Plan Position Indicator" (PPI) type display. It is in the shape of a sector and represents a top-down view of the area in front of the aircraft. The radar is located in the bottom centre of the display; the distance a target is from the centre point shows how far away it is, while its angle from the centre line shows its azimuth.\n\nWhen the radar is turned on, a bar representing the current scan angle sweeps back and forth, radially, about the centre point. A series of four concentric range rings can be used to determine how far away the detected targets are (to get the distance between rings divide the range scale by 4), and a series of bars (at 15-degree angles) help tell the azimuth of detected targets. If a radar has an azimuth scan angle of less than 180 degrees then the display is still a semicircle.\n\nThe readout to the left of the scope shows the azimuth and elevation scan angles, while the readout to the right shows the currently selected range scale.\n\nIn the image to the right there are three targets, all approximately 4.5 km away from the player. One target is at an azimuth of 0° (directly in front of the player) while one is at an azimuth of approximately -30° (30° to the left of the player), and one is at an azimuth of approximately +30° (30° to the right of the player). It is not possible to tell the target\'s elevation difference from the player using only the PPI.</string>

    <string name="c_scope_body">In addition to the PPI some aircraft have access to a C-scope type display (positioned underneath the PPI). The C-scope displays the same radar targets as the PPI, but in a different format. Whereas a PPI is a top-down view, the C-scope is forwards-looking. It is a rectangular display where how far from the azimuth centre line a target is shows its azimuth and how far from the elevation centre line a target is shows its elevation.\n\nIn addition to the azimuth and elevation centre lines there are two other horizontal lines on the display, these show the minimum and maximum elevation scan angles of the radar. It should be noted that the degree values shown to the right of the C-scope are the minimum and maximum elevation angles of the scope, not the radar.\n\nIn the image to the right there are three targets, all slightly below the player (they are below the elevation centre line). One target is at an azimuth of 0° (directly in front of the player) while one is at an azimuth of approximately -30° (30° to the left of the player), and one is at an azimuth of approximately +30° (30° to the right of the player). It is not possible to tell the target\'s range from the player using only the PPI.</string>

    <string name="b_scope_body">An alternative radar display (instead of the PPI) is available in the form of a B-Scope type display. It can be enabled via the Use rectangular radar indicator setting. It is a square display providing a 2-D top-down representation of space, the vertical axis represents the range to the target and the horizontal axis represents the azimuth (angle) of the target. The maximum and minimum azimuth scan angles are displayed in the top corners of the display, as is the range setting. A series of four range bars can be used to determine how far away detected targets are, and vertical bars can be used to determine what direction the target is in. When the radar is turned on a vertical bar representing the current scan angle moves horizontally, back and forth, across the display.</string>

    <string name="src_radar_mode_body">The Search (SRC) mode is the basic search radar mode. It is prone to ground clutter, or clouds cluttering it. This means if behind the enemy is something that reflects radar waves, the enemy will be hidden from your radar. So if you are looking downwards its not recommended to use this mode, but if you are looking upwards and there are no clouds in view you should can use this mode if no better is available.</string>

    <string name="src_pd_radar_mode_body">The Pulse-Doppler (PD) mode uses a signal processing filter, which eliminates out returns that have closure rate of your planes speed. So the ground will be filtered out, but also objects moving perpendicular towards your plane (so called notching). It also may have different blind spots resulting from the frequencies used in the radar, so that when chasing a target you might fail to get a lock on.</string>

    <string name="src_pd_hdn_radar_mode_body">It works like SRC PDN but is made for head-on engagements. Some radars will completely filter out targets that dont move towards you in this mode.</string>

    <string name="src_pdv_hdn_radar_mode_body">The display shows the targets not sorted by distance but by velocity. This makes it easier to select the target coming towards you at the fastest speed.</string>

    <string name="src_mti_radar_mode_body">MTI stands for moving target indication. It allows look-down capability, which means it filters out ground clutter. It is harder to notch than SRC PD but has a smaller range. Also even when the radar is able to maintain lock the missiles seeker might be not able to follow the target in a notching situation.</string>

    <string name="tws_radar_mode_body">Experience enhanced situational awareness with the Track While Scan radar, a game-changing technology in War Thunder. This advanced radar system allows players to simultaneously track multiple targets while continuously scanning the airspace, providing a significant tactical advantage in both air and ground combat scenarios. With TWS radar, pilots and tank commanders can maintain a broader view of the battlefield, manage threats more efficiently, and coordinate attacks with precision. Elevate your combat strategy by mastering this sophisticated radar technology, and dominate the skies and battlefields with superior intelligence and control.</string>

    <string name="tws_hdn_radar_mode_body">Works like TWS mode but shows only targets that fly towards you.</string>

    <string name="notching_body">Some radars have the ability to operate in pulse-Doppler mode, which analyses the Doppler effect on returned radar pulses to determine an object\'s velocity, and thus identify and track targets. In order for the radar to lock a target, it needs to have a significant Doppler shift (difference in velocity compared to the surroundings). This, however, cannot happen when the target is moving perpendicularly to the radar, as the target is not moving towards or away from the radar with a meaningful difference in speed. This perpendicular movement is called notching and is the main way to defeat a pulse-Doppler radar. The simplest way to do this is to put the direction where the enemy is coming from to your 3/9 o\'clock position, which makes your aircraft 90 degrees in relation to their radar. Keep in mind that notching will have minimal effect on a radar not operating in pulse-Doppler mode, and you should instead dive to take advantage of ground clutter.</string>

    <string name="tips_and_tricks_body">• If your radar is damaged (by gunfire or otherwise) you will not be able to turn it on until it is repaired\n\n• Left and right, up and down, on the radar display are relative to your aircraft, so if you roll the aircraft it can affect where targets are drawn on the radar display\n\n• Consider changing the default target locking key from Ctrl+ F to stop yourself from accidentally breaking your flaps if you mis-press the key combo.\n\n• Due to the raster scan pattern, targets may not be updated on every radar sweep, if you need more rapid updates try narrowing the search area.</string>

    <string name="clutter_body">Radars operate by emitting radio waves which then reflect off of targets and return to the radar. Unfortunately the radio waves also reflect off the ground, and other objects, leading to unwanted returns known as clutter. The type of clutter modelled in War Thunder is surface clutter (radar returns from the ground or sea).\n\nIn-game surface clutter is modelled as a green haze covering areas of the PPI, the more severe the ground clutter the more intense the haze gets. Anything more than mild surface clutter is usually enough to prevent the radar from picking up actual targets in the area the clutter is affecting. Likewise clutter can prevent tracking radars from effectively tracking targets.\n\nAs surface clutter is caused by reflections from the ground it is more pronounced when the radar is pointing downwards, and as such can prevent you from detecting targets which are below you in some situations. Different radars are affected by ground clutter to different extents, usually more modern radars are affected less than earlier ones</string>

</resources>